本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
Hey, you! Where's Tahamenay?!
おい　貴様　タハミーネはどこにおる
Mercy...
た…助け…
Huh? What? I can't tell what you're saying.
何言ってるか分からんな
Clean up the bodies along this path!
通路の死体を片づけろ
His Majesty, lnnocentis VII,
King of Lusitania, is making his entrance!
ルシタニア国王　イノケンティス七世陛下のご入城であるぞ
It stinks.
臭い
These aren't my words
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
They're probably our words
If the whole world only had left hands
片源
Rei
时间轴
电池雪糕
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
Don't be the bastards who hide their right hands
There's nothing beyond this azure
The day I realized that,
I stopped looking up at the sky
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You'd end up breathing in the bad stuff, too
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You are friend, Baby Dream
Before I knew it, my heart
Was full of things I had to love all the way
Always losing, leaving
Even the unbearable stuff
Because I don't want to live my days
I amenting, unable to keep them safe
You are friend, Baby, Dream
I'll grow even stronger
These aren't my words
But our words
Kill everyone, including
the priests and officials!
神官も役人も全て殺せ
The Queen has yet to be found!
王妃がまだ見つかってない
Find her!
捜し出せ
Yes, sir!
はっ
Did you find her?!
いたか
We have yet to come across her!
"Guest General, Kingdom of Lusitania
Lord Silver Mask"
まだ発見できません
All has gone to plan thus far.
"Guest General, Kingdom of Lusitania
Lord Silver Mask"
ここまでは予定どおり
Yes...
Pigs certainly dance
prettily when they get fed.
餌を与えられた豚はよく踊るものだな
Let this victory go to your heads.
今の勝利をおごるがよい
Damn Lusitanian savages.
ルシタニアの蛮人どもが
I hear the man in the silver mask
captured Queen Tahamenay.
銀仮面の男が王妃タハミーネを捕らえたそうだ
Well, well. Much credit
should go to him for that.
ほう　大手柄だな
Do you suppose that man truly does
serve Lusitania from the heart?
"General, Kingdom of Lusitania
Montferrat"
Baudouin"
やはりあの男　心から我がルシタニアに尽くしているのだろうか
Hard to say.
どうかな
His eyes behind the mask strike me
as uncanny and I do not like it.
どうにも　あの仮面の下の目が不気味で　俺は好かんよ
Here she comes.
来たぞ
"Queen, Kingdom of Pars
Tahamenay"
So, that is Tahamenay...
あれがタハミーネか
I hear she was first betrothed
初めはバダフシャーン公国宰相の婚約者であったそうだ
to the Grand Vizier of the
Principality of Badakhshan.
But his lord, Prince Keyumars,
stole her from him.
それを主君のカユーマルス公が奪った
A lord taking the betrothed
of one of his subjects...
臣下の婚約者を主君が…　か
A deed that can throw a kingdom into chaos.
国が乱れるゆえんだ
The poor Grand Vizier took his own life.
あわれな宰相は自殺
And later, the lord who stole
Tahamenay away also...
その後　タハミーネを奪った主君も
パルスの前王　オスロエスの侵攻に恐怖し　身投げ
...leapt to his death,
fearful of the invading Osroes,
the previous King of Pars.
After that, Osroes and his
younger brother, Andragoras,
その後　オスロエスとその弟アンドラゴラスは
fought over that woman and had a falling out.
あの女を取り合って仲たがい
Officially, Osroes died of illness,
オスロエスは病死ということになっているが
but they say that in truth,
Andragoras assassinated him
その実は　アンドラゴラスが暗殺して
and took both Tahamenay and the throne.
王位もタハミーネも手に入れたという話だ
A woman who brings misfortune to
every man who has dealings with her.
関わった男をことごとく不幸にする女
What is she? Some unearthly creature?
不気味な妖か
But her sorcery ends today.
だが　その妖力も今日までだ
His Majesty will never make
allowances for a heathen.
陛下が異教徒に手心を加えることはない
I wonder what sort of death
will be meted out to her...
あの女　どのような死が与えられるのか
Blush!
Prince Guiscard!
ギスカール様
Where might you be, Prince Guiscard?!
ギスカール様はいずこにおわしますか
Prince Guiscard!
ギスカール様
Such a racket. What is the matter?
騒々しい　何事だ
His Majesty is
i-i-impossible demand and...
陛下が　む　む…無理難題をおっしゃって　皆困っています
We are all at a loss.
兄者が　またか
My elder brother?
Again?
Something worthless, no doubt?
どうせ　ろくでもないことであろう
Will you not prevail upon him
to see sense, Prince Guiscard?
ギスカール様から説得していただけませぬか
I have many things that require my attention.
やらねばならぬことでいっぱいなんだ
All companies, check your
weapons and equipment!
各隊　武器装備の確認をしておけ
There is no knowing when the
Parsian survivors will come for us!
いつパルスの残党どもが来るか分からんぞ
So, what is it?
で　なんだ
His Majesty is insisting upon
making Tahamenay his queen!
陛下がタハミーネを妃にすると言って聞かないのです
What?
"Royal Brother, Kingdom of Lusitania Grand Vizier
and Supreme Commander of the Royal Army
Guiscard"
Ah! The wealth of Pars is
even greater than I had heard!
パルスの富は聞きしに勝りますな
Mm, this is most impressive!
これは見事だ
Brother!
兄者
Hm? What is it, Guiscard?
なんじゃ　ギスカール
Something about... wanting
to marry the Queen of Pars?
パルスの王妃をめとりたいとか
Yes, everyone is against it.
うん　皆が反対するのじゃ
Find some way to prevail upon them for me.
お主　なんとか説得してくれ
Brother...
兄者…
Are you aware of the miserable fates
あの女に関わった男どもの無残な末路をお知りですか
that befell the men who
had dealings with her?
It is beyond inauspicious.
あまりに不吉ですぞ
But those men were all heathens.
その男どもは全て異教徒ではないか
Or perhaps, God saw fit to test her.
あるいは　神が彼女に試練を授けたもうたのかもしれぬ
Wha...
なっ…
Perhaps, becoming the wife of
a devout follower of Yaldabaoth
敬虔なるイアルダボート教徒の妻になることこそ　彼女の運命かもしれぬ
is none other than her destiny.
Brother...
兄者…
You men there.
その方ら
It is God's great might that
has granted us this victory.
此度の勝利は神のお力によるものじゃ
全て神にささげるゆえ　決して手を付けてはならぬ
All of that will be offered up to God,
so you are not to take any of it.
はっ…ははっ
Y-Yes, sir.
This treasury will be placed entirely
under Archpriest Bodin's supervision.
この宝物庫の管理は全てボダン大司祭に任せる
なんですと
What did you say?!
It is our duty as God's faithful
to show our devotion.
神への信仰こそが我ら信徒の務めよ
Oh! I am tired. I will see you later.
疲れた　ではな
Brother!
兄者
I want to drink some sugar water.
砂糖水が飲みたい
Yes, sir! Right away!
ははっ　今すぐ
All of this to Bodin?!
ボダンに全てだと
Merely thinking of my brother possibly
having a child with that woman...
兄者にあの女との子なんぞできたらと考えるだけで…
It makes my stomach turn!
胃がねじ切れるわ
That will not happen.
そのようにはなりませぬ
You.
お主か
The man who has led the soldiers to this day
今日まで兵を率い　ルシタニアを勝利に導いた者は誰か
and guided Lusitania to victory...
The man who has the true makings of a king...
真に王の器たる人物が誰か
All of your subjects know who that man is.
それは　臣下の誰もが知るところ
However, there is a right time for these things.
だが　物事には機というものがございます
Endure for now, Your Highness.
今は耐えられよ　王弟殿下
Yes...
そうだな
That reminds me.
そういえば　アトロパテネの会戦の折はお主の策に助けられた
In the battle at Atropatene,
your strategies were of great help.
恐れ入ります
You do me great honor.
However, that fog...
しかし　あの霧　魔導士の業によるものだとうわさする者もいるが
There are some who say that
it was the work of sorcerers...
It was by the grace of the God of Yaldabaoth.
イアルダボート神のご加護にございますよ
You're in the way!
邪魔だ
I'm taking this.
もらうぞ
Y-Yes, as many as you wish.
は…はい　いくらでも
Damn Lusitanian soldiers.
ルシタニア兵め…
Acting like they own the place...
調子に乗りやがって
Offend them in the smallest way
and you'll be killed.
少しでも　ヤツらの機嫌を損ねると殺されるぞ
We can't do business like this!
商売にならねぇ
Those are Parsian soldiers. How?
パルス兵だ　どうして
Oh, that's probably Kharlan's
treasonous company.
あれは裏切り者のカーラーン隊だろ
The sneaky bastard who deserted
to the enemy at Atropatene.
アトロパテネで敵に寝返った卑怯者だ
Thank you.
ありがとう
That is...
あれは…
Hey.
Y-Yes, sir!
あっ　はい
H-How may we help you?
なんでしょうか
We run a show tent,
so we have nothing to give...
うちらは見せ物小屋なので　差し上げるものは何も…
That is not it.
そうではない
You have been here for
a long time, have you not?
お主ら　昔からここにおる者だな
Yes.
はい
ルシタニア人の奴隷を知らないか
Do you know of the Lusitanian slaves?
Huh?
I am looking for the Lusitanian soldiers
３年前　ここに連れてこられ　奴隷にされたルシタニア兵を捜している
who were brought here
three years ago to be slaves.
あれほど心して当たれと言ったではないか　役立たずどもめが
I went to great lengths to
warn you to be careful!
You useless fools!
"Treasonous Cavalry Captain
Kharlan"
My apologies!
申し訳ありません
下がれ
You are dismissed!
はっ
Yes, sir.
It seems they got led around
by the nose by this Narsus.
ナルサスとやらに手玉に取られたようだな
手ぬるいのではないか
Are you not being too easy on them?
I am truly ashamed of how
clumsily it has been handled.
誠に不甲斐ないことで
お主のことだ　手抜かりのあろうはずがない
Knowing you,
I am sure there were no
oversights on your part.
I will continue to expect
much of you, Erān Kharlan.
引き続き　期待しておるぞ
エーラーン・カーラーン
Yes, sir.
はっ
I will go ask Prince Guiscard for
permission to muster my men.
ギスカール公爵に兵を動かす許可を頂いてまいります
A traitor acting so high-and-mighty.
裏切り者がでかい面をしおって
A would-be vanquished man,
who has not even converted yet.
改宗も済ませぬ被征服民が　いつの間に我が軍に参画するようになったのやら
How did such a man come to
take part in our military plans?
It seems, rather than fighting for your life,
命懸けで戦うより　味方を売った方が出世への近道らしい
selling out your friends is the
faster way to rising up in the world.
Do you know of the Lusitanian slaves?
ルシタニア人の奴隷を知らぬか
３年前　奴隷商に売られた者たちだ
They were sold by a slaver three years ago.
I am looking for some people.
Is there anyone who knows of them?
人を捜している　誰か知っている者はおらぬか
すまぬ…　必ず助けに戻るなどと言っておきながら
I am sorry.
I promised to come back and
rescue all of you, and yet...
That boy who knew nothing of the world...
あの世間知らずの小僧
いいところの坊ちゃんのようだったな
He seemed like the pampered
son of a prominent family.
I wonder if they have a lot of slaves...
奴隷をたくさん使っているのだろうか
If I ask him, he may know...
あやつに聞けば何か…
いや
No...
A dolt like him would have long
since been killed by our army.
あんなまぬけはとっくに我が軍に殺されているか
Out of the way!
邪魔だ　道を開けよ
Clear the path!
また戦争かい
--Another battle?
--That's Lord Kharlan.
ありゃ　カーラーン様じゃないか
--He's no "lord" anymore.
--Shh!
もう　様じゃないよ
Hey, you there, girl.
おい　そこの娘
Do you find soldiers such a rare sight?
そんなに兵士が珍しいか
Oh, no, I was just wondering
what this procession was about.
あっ…　いえ　この隊列は何事かと思いまして
Oh, they're going to
capture the prince that fled.
ああ　これは逃げた王子を捕まえに行くんだ
王子がどこにいるか分かったのですか
They have found where the Prince is?
Who knows?
さあな
ただ　ヤツらも必死なのさ
But it's a desperate situation for them, too.
They betrayed the master they'd
served for many years to take our side.
長年仕えた主を裏切って我らに付いたんだ
It's probably messy for them
if the Prince remains alive.
王子が生き残ってちゃ　まずいんだろ
It's probably messy for them
if the Prince remains alive.
うわさでは　アンドラゴラス王も行方不明なのですってね
According to the rumors, I hear
King Andragonas is missing as well.
Yeah, seems that way.
ああ　そのようだ
そうだな　まっ　細かいことはこちらで話そうではないか
But yeah...
Well, why don't we talk
about it in detail over here?
--What is this? Please stop this!
--I'll tell you all about it in private.
なんですか　やめてください
二人っきりで教えてやるよ
Please have mercy! I converted
to the Faith of Yaldabaoth!
お許しください　私はイアルダボート教に改宗いたしました
Oh, did you now? Then all the more
reason for us to get friendly.
そうか　そうか　では　なおのこと　奥で仲よくしよう
Stop!
やめて
Hey, you!
おい　貴様
Damn...
Hey!
Release that... girl.
その娘を放…せ
You! You're no ordinary town girl, are you?!
貴様　ただの町娘ではないな
そちらも　ぼんくらなルシタニア兵ではないようだ
It seems you are no dimwit
Lusitanian soldier, either.
I serve Count Barcacion, a general
in the Lusitanian Royal Army!
ルシタニア国軍将軍　バルカシオン伯爵に仕える見習い騎士エトワールだ
I am his squire, Étoile!
娘　名を名乗れ
Girl, state your name!
Unfortunately, I have
no name worth stating.
あいにく　名乗るほどの名前は持ち合わせておりませぬゆえ
Coward!
卑怯者
捕まえ…
I have you!
A man?!
男
--Hey, what is it?
--What's going on?
Hey, it's a Lusitanian!
おい　ルシタニア兵だ
この…
A Lusitanian soldier?
ルシタニア兵
Slaves? Stay back.
奴隷か　下がっておれ
いつだ
When?
いつになったら　俺たちを自由民にしてくれるんだ
When will you make us free men?!
中から城門を開けるのを手伝ったんだぞ
We helped to open the gates from inside!
You promised to free us if
we aided you, remember?!
協力したら　解放してくれるって約束だろう
Wait!
待て…
I believed you people
and I killed my master!
あんたらを信じて　俺は主を殺したんだぞ
But nothing's been done for us!
なのに　何もしてもらえてない
We're going to starve to death at this rate!
このままじゃ　飢え死にだ
Stop!
待て
この
Why you...
--Give us money!
--Uh, but...
俺たちは自由民だ
金をくれ
--Give us land!
--Quickly!
土地をくれ
早く
なんだよ　なんか言えよ
王都は完全にルシタニアに落とされておりました
The Royal Capital was completely
under Lusitanian control.
父上は
What of my lord father?
兵士も町の者も　王がどこにいるのか知らぬようでした
Neither the soldiers nor the townspeople
seemed to know where the King was.
I see.
そうか
それから　カーラーンが殿下を捕らえようと　兵を率いて城を出ました
Also, Kharlan left the palace,
leading soldiers to capture Your Highness.
There were over a thousand cavalrymen.
１０００騎以上はいましたね
何
What?
Is that not somewhat excessive
for the purpose of capturing me?
私を捕らえるために　いささか大げさではないか
彼らは我々の数を知りませんからな
They do not know how
many we number, after all.
Not to mention, Your Highness
is a walking, talking just cause.
それに殿下は　歩く大義名分
If you were to be placed
at the head of an army,
あなたを陣頭に押し立てれば　ルシタニアに抵抗する勢力を糾合できます
we could rally together a force
that would stand against Lusitania.
ルシタニアにとっては　甚だまずいことですね
For Lusitania, that would
be extremely inconvenient.
だが　私の隠れている場所をどうやって見つけ出すつもりなのだろう
But how do you suppose they intend
to discover where I am hiding?
If I were Kharlan
私がカーラーンで　一刻も早く殿下を捕らえようと思ったら
and I wished to capture
Your Highness as quickly as possible,
まず　どこか適当な村を襲って焼きます
I would first attack some suitable village
and burn it down.
村を焼く
Burn down a village?!
その先はいくつか方法があります
After .that, there are several
ways I could go about it.
Burn the village, kill the villagers,
村を焼き　村人を殺し
and make a declaration of the
deed to extort Your Highness.
それを布告して殿下を脅迫するのが　まず一つ
That is one way.
For as long as Your Highness
does not make an appearance,
殿下が出頭しないかぎり
I burn village after village,
killing innocent people.
次々と村を焼き　罪なき者を殺します
There are many other ways, but...
他にもいろいろありますが…
W-Wait! Would Kharlan go so far?
ま…待て
カーラーンがそこまでするだろうか　あれでも　彼は武人だ
He is still a warrior!
王と国を売った模範的な武人ですな
A most exemplary warrior,
who sold out his king and country.
ナルサス
Narsus.
Can you tell which village Kharlan will attack?
カーラーンがどこの村を襲うか分かるか
Certainly.
分かりますとも
How?
どうやって
彼の部隊が案内してくれます
His company will lead the way.
We must merely follow them.
後ろに付けばよろしい
Shall we do that?
そうなさいますか
We leave immediately! Saddle the horses!
すぐに出る　鞍の用意を
Narsus, Kharlan is not a simple man.
ナルサス　カーラーンは単純な男ではない
Forming up for all to see and leaving
the Royal Capital in broad daylight...
白昼あからさまに隊を組んで　王都を出るなど…
殿下を誘い出す罠か
A trap to lure His Highness out?
That is a possibility.
ありえることだな
そう思うなら　なぜお止めせぬ
If you think so, then why not stop him?
ダリューンよ　俺は結構あの王子の器量に期待しているのだ
Daryun, in truth, I have high hopes
for that prince as a man of caliber.
And in any event, unless we
hear it from Kharlan himself,
どのみち　カーラーンの口からでなくては
we have no way of knowing
the circumstances behind this.
裏面の事情も知りようもない
獅子の子を捕らえるためだ
We are out to capture a lion cub.
At times, that may necessitate
going into the lion's den.
獅子の巣に入り込むのも　時にやむをえぬだろうよ
Had His Highness not
set out to save the village,
お前　殿下が村を救いに行かぬときは
you were planning to
deem him unfit to be a ruler
君主たる者の資格なしと見なして　見放すつもりだったのではないか
and forsake him, were you not?
Daryun! Narsus! Let us leave quickly!
ダリューン　ナルサス　早く出よう
A village may be under
attack even as we speak!
こうしている間にも　村が襲われているかもしれない
Whoa-oh, Lusitanian soldiers, huh?
よっと　ルシタニア兵か
Better to avoid any unnecessary conflicts.
余計な争いはしない方がいい
Just as I had heard, the villages in
the area seem to have been hit hard.
うわさどおり　辺りの村はかなりやられているな
Well, not that it is any concern of mine.
まっ　俺には関係ないがね
Mm! A fine woman,
the likes of whom I rarely see!
めったにいないよい女だ
若い分　うそつき王妃を上回るな
And her youth puts her
above the deceitful Queen.
Wait, this is bad.
っと　いかん
Up ahead are those Lusitanian soldiers.
この先には先ほどのルシタニア兵が
That woman will be attacked.
あのご婦人が襲われてしまう
And that is when I will rescue her.
そこを俺が助ける
Naturally, she will be grateful
and hold me in high esteem.
当然ながら　俺には感謝敬愛の念を抱く
そして　何かお礼をしなくてはと考えるだろう
And she will surely think that she
ought to repay me in some way.
そうなるだろう　そうなるといい
That is surely how it will be.
I hope that is how it will be.
That is how it ought to be!
そうなるべきだ
よし　追いかける
All right, I am going after her!
女
Woman.
一人でどこへ行くつもりだ
Where do you think you are going alone?
Do you behave in this way,
俺たちが戦勝のルシタニア兵だと知っての態度か
knowing we are soldiers
of the victorious Lusitania?
おお　幸運の女神アシよ
Oh, Ashi, Goddess of Fortune!
I see that you have wasted
no time bestowing your favor
あなたの信徒のうちで最も容姿端麗なこの美丈夫に
upon this comely man, your follower
with the fairest of face and figure.
早速ご加護をたれたもうたか
W-Wait, woman!
ま…待て　女
Why you!
貴様
待て
Stop!
H-Hey, is this a joke?
お…おい　冗談
At this rate, I will have no
chance to put her in my debt!
このままでは　恩を売る機会がなくなってしまう
What...
なんだ
So, they flee. Wise of them.
逃げるか　賢明だな
危ういところでしたな　ご婦人
That was close, madam.
If I, Gieve, had not just
happened to pass by...
このギーヴがたまたま通りかからなかったら…
この状況で　シカト
Ignoring me... after that?
Please wait! You there, madam!
お待ちあれ　そこのご婦人
You there, the beautiful lady!
そこの美人
そこの絶世の美女
You there, the exquisite beauty!
私を呼んだか
Are you addressing me?
ただの美女というならともかく
Simply a beauty is one thing,
but there are not so many exquisite
beauties around, after all.
絶世の美女といえば　そうはおらぬゆえ
Well, not only are you beautiful,
but you are skilled in the martial arts.
いや　あなたの美しさに加え　武芸の冴え
誠に感服いたしました
I am truly struck with admiration.
My name is Gieve.
我が名は　ギーヴ
I have no home to call my own
and I am a traveling musician.
住む家もなき旅の楽士ながら
美をめでる心は　王侯貴族にも勝るものとうぬぼれている
Yet, I flatter myself that I am a man
with a greater appreciation for beauty
than even princes and nobles.
今　乏しい詩心を奮って　あなたを賛美する詩を作ったところだ
Just now, I made the most of
my meager talent for verse
and composed a poem to sing your praises.
その姿は糸杉のごとくすらりと伸び
Her form, svelte and straight as a cypress tree
黒き髪は夜空の一部を切り取り
Her black hair, a piece
carved out of the night sky
And her eyes, putting emeralds to shame--
瞳はエメラルドをしのぎ…
As a wandering minstrel,
you lack in originality.
お主　吟遊詩人としては独創性に欠けるな
Well, it is true that I am wanting as a poet.
まあ　詩人としては確かに未熟でござるが…
But I will say it again.
重ねて言うが　美と正義を愛する心は　古の大詩人にも劣らぬつもりだ
I believe my love of beauty and justice
is equal to that of the great poets of old.
Which is exactly why I was
conveniently able to rescue you.
だからこそ　都合よくあなたをお救いできた
都合よく　お救い
Conveniently? Rescue me?
If it please you, would you
not tell me your name?
よろしければ　名を聞かせてはもらえないか
私の名はファランギース
My name is Farangis.
フゼスターン地方のミスラ神殿に仕える者じゃ
I serve the Temple of Mithra
in the Khūzestān region.
I was sent to the Royal Capital
of Ecbatana as an emissary.
"Priestess, Temple of Mithra
Farangis"
使者として　王都エクバターナに遣わされてな
Ah, the Divine Mithra!
ほう　ミスラ神
After I pay my respects to the Goddess Ashi,
俺はアシ女神に次ぐ尊敬を　ミスラ神に対して　お払い申し上げている
it is the Divine Mithra
to whom I turn next.
You and I share no ordinary
connection, Mistress Farangis.
ファランギース殿とはただならぬ因縁…　いや　運命と言っても…
Nay! One might even call it fate--
だが　王都はすでに落ちたという
However, I hear that the
Royal Capital has already fallen.
すごすご帰るわけにもいかず
I could not very well go home in defeat,
so I was thinking of at least
finding lodgings for the night...
ともかく今夜の宿を　と思っているうちに
And that was when I ran
into those Lusitanian dogs.
ルシタニアの犬どもに出会ってしもうたのじゃ
I have seen it along the way,
but their savagery has been truly inhuman.
道々見てきたが　ヤツらの蛮行は誠にむごいものであった
Ah, I saw that for myself as well.
おお　それは俺も見てきたところだ
They say they serve their god,
ヤツら　神に仕えると言いながら
慈悲慈愛の心を全く持ち合わせておらん
but they have absolutely no love
or compassion in their hearts.
Even among the Parsians,
パルス人の中にも　どさくさに紛れて神殿の財をかすめ取り
I hear some have taken
advantage of the chaos
to rob temples of their riches
王都を捨てる輩がいるとか
and then turn their backs
upon the Royal Capital.
このファランギース　神に仕える身として　誠に嘆かわしく思う
As someone who serves a god,
I, Farangis, find it truly I lamentable.
So, what business was it
that brought you here?
で　どのような御用がおありだったのかな
I was on my way to see His Highness,
the Crown Prince Arslan.
王太子　アルスラーン殿下のもとへ参ろうとしておったのじゃ
Please have mercy!
お許しください
We know nothing! It is the truth!
私どもは何も知りません　本当です
Why are soldiers of Pars attacking Parsians?!
なぜパルスの兵がパルス人を襲うのですか
What happened?!
何があったのですか
焼き殺せ
Burn them to death.
ただし　男たちだけだ
--But only the men.
--Stop this!
やめろ
お待ちください　私たちは本当に何も知らないのです
Please wait! We really do not know anything!
Then let it be known to your neighbors!
ならば　近隣に触れ回れ
アルスラーンとその一党をかくまえば
Any community that gives shelter
to Arslan and his company
will be massacred, including
the women and children!
女子供も皆殺しにするとな
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go, drifting
When a tale that is shapeless
Spreads across the moonlight
The treasure that is within you
Melts away into the wind now
Tomorrow, try to take
wing as your unvarnished self
Sometime, somewhere,
you wanted this, remember?
You can hear it, can't you?
There; that shining dream from that day
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go
Oh, 'til this dream comes to an end
In Kharlan's voice, there was
something too dark and ruthless
カーラーンの声には
単なる嘲弄と呼ぶには　陰惨すぎる響きがあった
for it to be described as simple derision.
次回　裏切りの英雄
Next time, "The Treasonous Hero."
And thus, the boy would become king.
少年は　そして王となる